<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>dclogin, Author at Neuro Radiology Expert</title>
	<atom:link href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/blog/author/dclogin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:13:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/cropped-Siteicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>dclogin, Author at Neuro Radiology Expert</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How Expert Neuroradiology Saved a Family from Misjudgement</title>
		<link>https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/blog/how-expert-neuroradiology-saved-a-family-from-misjudgement/</link>
					<comments>https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/blog/how-expert-neuroradiology-saved-a-family-from-misjudgement/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dclogin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 07:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/?p=17370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered what happens when a single misread medical scan turns someone’s life upside down? Imagine being a parent who is suddenly accused of harming their own child, all because an imaging report was interpreted incorrectly. Unfortunately, that’s [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/blog/how-expert-neuroradiology-saved-a-family-from-misjudgement/">How Expert Neuroradiology Saved a Family from Misjudgement</a> appeared first on <a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com">Neuro Radiology Expert</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Have you ever wondered what happens when a single misread medical scan turns someone’s life upside down? Imagine being a parent who is suddenly accused of harming their own child, all because an imaging report was interpreted incorrectly. Unfortunately, that’s not a hypothetical; it’s exactly what happened in a case that reminds us why, in high-stakes situations, precision in neuroradiology isn’t optional- it’s imperative.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To help make things clearer, this is the story of how a 7-month-old infant was misdiagnosed as a victim of child abuse, and how </span><a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/about-us/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">expert neuroradiologists</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;"> are helping to uncover the truth.</span></p>
<h2><b>A Diagnosis that Changed Everything</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">When the baby was brought to the emergency department with seizures, the initial CT and MRI scans showed subdural and intraparenchymal bleeding and skull fractures. That report alone was enough for authorities to intervene.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">After the report, the father lost custody, the child was removed from the home, and supervised visits became the only way in which he could see his child for years. Can you imagine the devastation, the helplessness, and the emotional toll the father would have faced? And for two long years, the initial interpretation stood unchallenged.</span></p>
<h2><b>How A Second Look from a Specialist Changed the Game?</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dr. Hazany was then consulted to review the case, and what he found completely rewrote the narrative. He didn’t just glance over the scans; he re-examined the entire CT/MRI series along with the skeletal survey, and his findings concluded:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The bleeding pattern wasn’t consistent with trauma at all.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It was due to venous-sinus occlusion with reflux bilateral brain parenchymal and subdural hemorrhage, which is a medical condition, not abuse.</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;" aria-level="1"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The supposed “skull fractures” were primarily normal cranial suture variants that are common in infants.</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In other words, the original conclusion of non-accidental trauma was simply wrong.</span></p>
<h2><b>The Outcome: Truth Restored and Family Reunited</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once Dr. Hazany’s analysis was presented, the entire abuse allegation collapsed. Custody restrictions were lifted, and the defense team avoided a risky trial. The case is now moving toward dismissal, and even proposing a motion for damages.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This wasn’t just a win; it was a life restored, a family reunited, and a formidable example of how subspecialty neuroradiology can turn the tide in wrongful-abuse cases.</span></p>
<p><b><i>Quick Snapshot of the Case:</i></b></p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><b>Aspect</b></td>
<td><b>Details</b></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Matter type</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Wrongful child abuse (non-accidental trauma) allegation (defense)</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Patient</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">7-month-old infant with seizures</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Initial interpretation</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Bilateral subdural and intraparenchymal bleed + Skull fractures</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Expert finding</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">Venous-sinus occlusion; normal sutures</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Outcome</b></td>
<td><span style="font-weight: 400;">The allegation was withdrawn, and custody was restored.</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2><b>The Significance of This Case for Attorneys</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In pediatrics, the line between trauma, pathology related to underlying disease, and normal development is thin… unless you know exactly what you are looking at.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">As Dr. Hazany puts it:</span></p>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">“The takeaway is that image interpretation demands subspecialty expertise.”</span></i></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is why attorneys and judges increasingly rely on credentialed expert neuroradiologists to challenge incorrect diagnoses, and as a result, reduce trial risk and strengthen their case strategy from day one.</span></p>
<h2><b>Conclusion</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In medicine, misinterpretation can cost lives. In the legal system, it can cost families. But when specialized neuroradiology steps in, it can make a world of difference between a broken family and a healed one.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Need expert neuroradiology support? From high-credibility imaging reviews to </span><a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/our-services/forensic-neuroradiology/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">expert witness support</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, the subspecialty neuroradiologists at </span><a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Neuro Experts, PC</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, provide the precision and clarity your case deserves. Reach out today to ensure your next case is backed by authoritative, courtroom-ready expertise.</span></p>
<p>The post <a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/blog/how-expert-neuroradiology-saved-a-family-from-misjudgement/">How Expert Neuroradiology Saved a Family from Misjudgement</a> appeared first on <a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com">Neuro Radiology Expert</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/blog/how-expert-neuroradiology-saved-a-family-from-misjudgement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Neuro Experts are Revolutionizing Forensic TBI Analysis</title>
		<link>https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/blog/how-neuro-experts-are-revolutionizing-forensic-tbi-analysis/</link>
					<comments>https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/blog/how-neuro-experts-are-revolutionizing-forensic-tbi-analysis/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[dclogin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/?p=17286</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you have ever wondered how doctors and scientists uncover what really happens inside the brain after a traumatic brain injury (TBI), you are about to be amazed. The brain is a beautifully complex organ, and when it suffers trauma- [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/blog/how-neuro-experts-are-revolutionizing-forensic-tbi-analysis/">How Neuro Experts are Revolutionizing Forensic TBI Analysis</a> appeared first on <a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com">Neuro Radiology Expert</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[		<div data-elementor-type="wp-post" data-elementor-id="17286" class="elementor elementor-17286" data-elementor-post-type="post">
						<section class="elementor-section elementor-top-section elementor-element elementor-element-22726e79 elementor-section-boxed elementor-section-height-default elementor-section-height-default mkdf-parallax-row-no mkdf-content-aligment-left mkdf-elementor-row-grid-no mkdf-disabled-bg-image-bellow-no" data-id="22726e79" data-element_type="section">
						<div class="elementor-container elementor-column-gap-default">
					<div class="elementor-column elementor-col-100 elementor-top-column elementor-element elementor-element-1ece957f" data-id="1ece957f" data-element_type="column">
			<div class="elementor-widget-wrap elementor-element-populated">
						<div class="elementor-element elementor-element-c58f842 elementor-widget elementor-widget-text-editor" data-id="c58f842" data-element_type="widget" data-widget_type="text-editor.default">
				<div class="elementor-widget-container">
									<p>If you have ever wondered how doctors and scientists uncover what really happens inside the brain after a traumatic brain injury (TBI), you are about to be amazed. The brain is a beautifully complex organ, and when it suffers trauma- whether from an accident, a fall, or a blast- understanding the full impact isn’t as simple as a scan or test. That’s where <a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/">Neuro Experts</a> step in with their comprehensive approach to forensic TBI neuroimaging, which combines advanced science, expert insight, and technology to uncover the hidden truths behind brain injuries.</p><p> </p><h2><strong>A Multi-Dimensional Approach to TBI Analysis</strong></h2><p>Think about it: what happens when two people experience similar head trauma, but one fully recovers while the other struggles with memory loss, fatigue, and mood changes for years? If this is the case and you are wondering why this is happening, the answer often lies in the details —details that conventional CT or MRI scans may miss.</p><p>Neuro Experts bridge that gap through a layered evaluation process that combines neuropsychological testing, EEG analysis, and advanced neuroimaging. When it comes to brain injuries, one method isn’t enough, which is why Neuro Experts take a comprehensive, multi-step approach to ensure that no subtle change goes unnoticed.</p><p> </p><table><tbody><tr><td width="150"><strong>Component</strong></td><td width="150"><strong>Purpose</strong></td><td width="150"><strong>What It Reveals</strong></td></tr><tr><td><strong>Neuropsychological Testing</strong></td><td>Assesses cognitive and emotional function</td><td>The impact on memory, attention, and overall behavior</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Clinical Neurological Assessment</strong></td><td>Examines physical and motor symptoms</td><td>Reflexes, coordination, and movement disorders</td></tr><tr><td><strong>EEG Analysis</strong></td><td>Measure brainwave activity</td><td>Seizures, sleep abnormalities, or slowed brain function</td></tr><tr><td><strong>Neuroradiology/ Neuroimaging</strong></td><td>Visualizes structural and functional changes</td><td>Brain damage, atrophy, or connectivity issues</td></tr></tbody></table><p>Each layer of clinical neurological assessment adds another piece to the puzzle, which paints a fuller picture of how the injury has affected the brain and its functions. In fact, one of the most fascinating advancements in this field is <a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/blog/diffusion-tensor-imaging-dti-in-mild-traumatic-brain-injury-mtbi/">Diffusion Tensor Imaging for TBI</a>, which is a specialized MRI technique for mapping the brain’s white matter pathways.</p><p> </p><p><strong style="color: #0c0c0c; font-size: 30px;">The Science Behind the Diagnosis</strong></p><p><em>A study revealed that as many as 56% of TBIs go undetected in the ER. (</em><a href="https://biausa.org/public-affairs/media/prompt-diagnosis-and-treatment-of-traumatic-brain-injuries-starts-in-the-emergency-room"><em>Source</em></a><em>)</em>. That’s a massive gap in diagnosis, and Neuro Experts aim to close this gap through advanced TBI neuroimaging. By examining both structure and function, advanced imaging techniques offer measurable, objective evidence of brain damage, which is particularly critical in forensic cases involving legal or insurance disputes.</p><p>This high level of precision doesn’t just support clinical care; it also provides clarity in the courtroom. Whether it’s about verifying the extent of the injury or establishing causation, Neuro Experts combine technology and expertise to ensure that every assessment is backed by science and supported by data.</p><h2><strong>The Bottom Line</strong></h2><p>Most people don’t realize this, but the human brain is like a vast city of connections, and after a traumatic event, some of these “roads” might get blocked, rerouted, or broken entirely. <a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/our-services/forensic-neuroradiology/">Neuro Experts’ forensic TBI analysis</a> combines the best of neurology, psychology, and imaging science to identify these changes and provide patients and professionals with the answers they deserve. In a world where invisible injuries often go unrecognized, their work is helping to make the unseen, seen.</p>								</div>
				</div>
					</div>
		</div>
					</div>
		</section>
				</div>
		<p>The post <a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/blog/how-neuro-experts-are-revolutionizing-forensic-tbi-analysis/">How Neuro Experts are Revolutionizing Forensic TBI Analysis</a> appeared first on <a href="https://neuroradiologyexpert.com">Neuro Radiology Expert</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://neuroradiologyexpert.com/blog/how-neuro-experts-are-revolutionizing-forensic-tbi-analysis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
